(銀時)お～い 帰ったぞ｡
うるせえなぁ…｡
いちご牛乳 持ってこい｡
(叫び声)
男と犬はなぁ
２～３日 目 離すと➡
やたら 定春が でかく見えるぞ｡
なんだ まだ起きてねえのか？
まったく なまけ者どもが…｡
銀さんが帰ってきたよ～っと｡
なんだ やっぱり 飲みすぎたな｡
(神楽)定春が… 定春が
一夜にして 巨大化したね！
おい 新八 そんなところに
頭 突っ込んでないで➡
(新八)なに 寝ぼけたこと
言ってんすか！ この状況を見ろ!!
お～い いちご牛… にゅ…｡
あ～ 気持悪… うっ！
誰か～
いちご牛乳 持って… うっ…｡
別人のように
大きくなるってもんなんだよ｡
ｱﾝﾀは 何日 経っても
ずっと平行線で ﾀﾞﾒ人間だけどな！
Hey, I'm home.
Gin-san's back.
I feel like shit.
Somebody... Bring me...Strawberry milk...
What? Nobody's awake?
Man, you lazy bums...
Hey, my strawberry mil...?!
What the... I guess I had too much to drink, after all.
Sadaharu looks awfully huge.
Hey, Shinpachi, get your head out of there and bring me my strawberry milk.
Are you still half asleep or something?!
Can't you see what's happening?!
Sadaharu! Sadaharu turned giant overnight!
Don't bother me with that.
Just a few days passed since I last saw him. Men and dogs hit growth spurts all the time.
You remain hopeless no matter how many days pass!
[Dear viewers, thank you for your honest opinions and feedback, as always.]
[Today, we have a cute dog story, so you can relax and enjoy the show.]
["Walk Your Dog at an Appropriate Speed"]
Sadaharu loves strawberry milk.
(神楽)定春は
いちご牛乳が 好物よ｡
(神楽)大きくなったけど
性格は変わってないね｡
He's gotten bigger, but his personality hasn't changed.
でも いったい なんで
こんなことに…｡
But how in the world did he become like this?
お前らが むやみに
ｶﾙｼｳﾑなんか摂らせるから➡
It's because you blindly gave him too much calcium.
こんな でかくなるんだよ｡
ｶﾙｼｳﾑ ﾅﾒんなよ｡
Don't underestimate calcium. Taking calcium makes everything better.
ｶﾙｼｳﾑさえ摂っときゃ
すべて うまくいくんだよ｡
ｱﾝﾀ 全然
うまくいってないじゃないですか｡
And yet, you're still as stupid as ever.
それより
いったい どうするんですか？
More importantly, though, what are we going to do? He's gotten so huge.
こんなに大きくなっちゃって…｡
It'll be fine, Shinpachi-kun. For times like these...
大丈夫だよ 新八君｡
こんなときは…｡
たらりらったら～！
｢わんじゃこりゃああ｣!!
I have the extraordinary "Ruff Translator."
これさえあれば
犬が 何をしゃべってるか➡
With this, we can understand anything Sadaharu says!!
その鳴き声から わかるんだ｡
いつのまに そんな便利なｱｲﾃﾑを！
Where'd you pick up such a convenient device?!
昨日 飲み屋で 隣の親父に
枝豆と交換してもらったんだ｡
Yesterday at the bar, I traded my edamame with the guy sitting next to me.
うさんくささ
100ﾊﾟｰｾﾝﾄじゃねえか!!
That's 100 percent suspicious!
とりあえず これなら➡
For now, we might be able to learn why he grew so huge and how to reverse it.
でかくなった理由も 解決策も
わかるかもしんねえ｡
定春 お前 どうして
そんなに でかくなったんだ？
Sadaharu, how did you get so big?
おい なんとか言え！
Hey, say something!
(定春)わぎゃあ！
ぶべらっ!!
(機械音)
[That hurt. I'll report you to the Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals, dammit!]
(神楽)
合ってるっちゃあ 合ってるｱﾙ｡
I think it works...
Damn dog! That's no way to treat your master!
この野郎！
ご主人様に 何しやがんだぁ!!
ﾌﾌﾝ 次は 私の番ね｡
My turn next.
私は 定春 いつも
かわいがってるから 大丈夫ね｡
I'm always taking good care of Sadaharu, so he'll be nice to me.
定春 とりあえず
私への日頃の感謝を➡
Sadaharu, tell them how much you like me!
言ってみるｱﾙ｡
ﾜﾝ｡
[More than the readers, who only ranked you 7th in the JUMP popularity poll.]
You! How do you know that?!
ﾃﾒｴ！ なんで
そんなこと 知ってんだ!?
落ち着いて 神楽ちゃん！
ﾎﾞｸなんか ８位だぞ!!
Calm down, Kagura-chan. I was only 8th, you know.
ぐおぉ～っ!!
Guess I have no choice.
しようがないな｡
なんだかんだ言って➡
After all is said and done, the one who took care of Sadaharu the most was me.
定春の世話を
いちばん してたの ﾎﾞｸだもんね｡
定春 ﾎﾞｸのいうことは
きいてくれるよね？
ﾜﾝ！
Sadaharu, you'll listen to me, right?
黒っ！ こんな白い犬なのに➡
[Sure, you take care of me... When you're not obsessing over that stupid girl idol or being the butt of everyone else's jokes. You're pathetic!]
You're so mean-spirited! How can such a white dog have such a black heart?!
腹の中 黒っ!! っていうか 長え！
And how can one bark mean that much?!
こんな長い意味あんの!?
Wait!! I'm the butt of a joke again!
って また ﾂｯｺんじまったぁ!!
(神楽)なんだ この ｲﾝﾁｷ翻訳機！
This thing is a piece of junk!
枝豆 返せ この野郎！
Give me back my edamame, old man!
(機械音)
(神楽)苦しい？
[It hurts.]
It hurts?
故障かな？
ｵﾚは 二日酔いで苦しいよ｡
Maybe it's broken.
I'm hurting from a hangover.
(神楽)助けて｡
[Help me.]
Help me?
We're the ones who need help. What're we going to do?
こっちが助けてほしいわ｡
どうすんだ これ｡
なんだ さっきから ﾒｷﾒｷ ﾒｷﾒｷ｡
夏期講習で 学力ｱｯﾌﾟか？
What's that sound? Somebody eating pocky sticks or something?
(女性)なに あれ！
(男性)犬？ 犬か あれ！
What is that?!
A dog? Is that a dog?!
(ｷｬｽﾀｰ)え～ 続いての記事です｡
Moving on to our next story...
Ana Ketsuno, Japan's most popular weather forecaster,
あの お天気おねえさんとして
人気を博した 結野ｱﾅが➡
先月末 離婚していたことが
発覚しました｡
filed for divorce late last month.
And after being married for only three months! She stated a difference in values as the reason.
Seems she left him after all. I always knew they would break up.
(百音)あ～
やっぱり別れましたわね｡
(百音)どうせ すぐ別れると
思ってましたのよ 私｡
(百音)なにが
価値観の相違ですか｡
Difference in values, my foot. It's a difference in values is what make marriage interesting.
価値観なんて それぞれ違うから
おもしろいんでしょうに｡
ねぇ 狛子ちゃん｡
(狛子)ﾜﾝ｡
Right, Komako-chan?
(阿音)ろくに
恋愛したこともない女が➡
Don't talk when you haven't even experienced love.
語ってるんじゃないわよ！
巫女が 清らかな体 守って
何が悪いんですか？
What's wrong with a miko keeping her body pure? I'm not a hussy like you, older sister.
(Note: A miko is a virginal shrine maiden)
私は 姉上のようなｱﾊﾞｽﾞﾚとは
違いますのよ｡
なんだと このｸｿｱﾏ！
What was that, you little bitch?! Who do you think keeps you fed around here?!
誰のおかげで
ﾒｼ食っていけると思ってんだ！
(百音)巫女なんて
ｸﾞｰﾀﾗ祈ってればいいんでしょ｡
All miko have to do is be idle and pray.
If just praying made the money come pouring down, I'd be praying, too!
(阿音)祈って 金が降ってくるなら
私だって 祈り続けるわ！
(阿音)いい？ 私たち
もう 巫女なんかじゃないの｡
Listen! We're not miko anymore! We're just regular, respectable, working girls.
人間として 女として 立派に
生きていかなきゃいけないの！
立派～？
Respectable?
What's respectable about a miko, who forsakes their god and works at a hostess bar?
神子を捨てて ｷｬﾊﾞｸﾗ勤めの巫女の
どこが立派なのですか？
(阿音)あのときは
ああするしかなかったの！
Back then, I had no choice!
I gave up my life as a miko and decided to live as a hostess bar priestess.
あのときから 私は 巫女を捨て
ｷｬﾊﾞｸﾗ巫女として➡
生きていくことに決めたの！
捨ててないでしょ｡
You haven't given it up. You're using it to your advantage.
利用してるでしょ
巫女であることを｡
(阿音)巫女ってだけで
ﾊﾞｶな男どもが寄ってくんのよ！
Foolish men flock to me just because of the word "miko."
狛子ちゃん うるさいですよ｡
(狛子の吠え声)
Komako-chan, please be quiet.
And now, we take you to...
(ｷｬｽﾀｰ)それでは
突如 巨大な犬が現れた➡
Kabukicho, where a giant dog has suddenly appeared.
現場の かぶき町から 中継です｡
(ｷｬｽﾀｰ)現場の花野ｱﾅ｡
あれ？ あれ ちょっと…｡
Huh? Isn't that...?
We have announcer Hanano on the scene. Announcer Hanano?
[Note: Hanano ana is a play on hana no ana, the word for nostril.]
(花野ｱﾅ)
現場の花野です｡
This is Hanano at the scene.
[Kabukicho, Edo]
[Announcer Hanano]
I'm about to interview the owners of the giant dog.
では 早速
巨大犬の飼い主に➡
直撃してみたいと
思います｡
[Giant dog owner A, feeding the dog]
(花野ｱﾅ)あの すみません｡
Excuse me. We're from Edo Tonight...
(花野ｱﾅ)大江戸ﾃﾚﾋﾞですが…｡
ん？
Hey! Get that camera off me!
あ～ ちょっと
撮らないでくださいよ！
Um...the entire neighborhood is quite troubled by the giant dog.
(花野ｱﾅ)あの～ 巨大犬のせいで➡
近所の方々は たいへん
迷惑されているんですが➡
そのへん
どう お考えなんですか？
What do you have to say about it?
すみませ～ん！
I'm sorry!
No, we're not looking for an apology...
(花野ｱﾅ)いや
すみませ～ん じゃなくて…｡
I'm sorry! I apologize to everyone in the world!
すみません！ 世界じゅうの
みんなに すみません!!
I said, we're not looking for an apology.
(花野ｱﾅ)いや
すみません じゃなくて…｡
(布団を叩く音)
[Giant dog owner B]
Excuse me, my name is Hanano. I'm from Edo Tonight.
(花野ｱﾅ)あの すみません｡
(花野ｱﾅ)大江戸ﾃﾚﾋﾞの
花野と申しますが…｡
(神楽)また お前らか！
You people again?! Are you that intent on making us the bad guys?
私たちを
そんなに 悪者にしたいか！
それが ﾏｽﾒﾃﾞｨｱか！
Is this what the mass media does?!
(神楽)帰れ！ 帰れ！
Go away! Go away!
(神楽)さっさと帰れ!!
(花野ｱﾅ)帰りません！
Go home! Get out of here right now!
We're not leaving. That attitude will just isolate you from your neighbors.
そんな態度でいると
近所から 孤立しますよ｡
Announcer... Hanano... is having an affair with the show's anchor!
(神楽)花野！ ｱﾅは！
司会者と不倫!!
(花野ｱﾅ)なに
ﾃﾞﾀﾗﾒ言ってんだ ｺﾗｧ！
Am not!! Am not!!
[Giant dog owner C]
Excuse me! I'm from Edo...
あの すみません！ 大江戸…！
おいおい ﾀﾞﾒだよ
急に飛び出してきちゃあ｡
Hey, hey, don't jump in front of me like that.
あの… 巨大犬の…｡
About the...giant dog...
あれ なんで ｶﾒﾗあんだ？
『ﾚﾃﾞｨｽ４』の取材？
Huh? What's with the camera?
Is this an interview for "Ladies 4"?
[Note: Ladies 4 is an afternoon talk show aimed at the housewife demographic.]
ｷﾞｬ～ｯ！ ﾁｬｯｸ開いてます 前!!
Your fly is open! In front!
In front? Of the camera? Around here?
前？ あ ｶﾒﾗの前 このへん？
Hey! Stop the camera! Stop it!
(花野ｱﾅ)
ちょっと！ ｶﾒﾗ止めて！ ｶﾒﾗ!!
...Oh my god...
まいったなぁ おい｡
まさか 全国ﾈｯﾄで
ﾁｬｯｸを全開していたとはよ…｡
I never thought my fly would be open on national TV.
そこかよ｡
Not there.
(お登勢)どうすんだい
こんな大事になっちまって…｡
What're you going to do? It's become a huge incident.
The Sad-chan manju aren't selling at all now. Get out.
[Note: Sad-chan manju are bean jam cakes made in the shape of Sadaharu]
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)定ちゃんまんじゅうも
全然 売れねえし もう出てけよ｡
お～い 誰の許可 得て
商品化してんだ｡
Who gave you permission to make Sadaharu merchandise?
まぁな ｱﾝﾀらにも
いろいろ迷惑かけちまって➡
Well, we've put you folks through a lot of trouble.
ここらが潮時かもな｡
Maybe it's time for us to leave. People who can't mind their manners have no right to keep a pet.
ﾏﾅｰを守れねえﾔﾂに
ﾍﾟｯﾄを飼う資格はねえもんな｡
銀さん…｡
Gin-san...
But abandoning such a huge pet isn't going to be easy.
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)でも 捨てるにしても➡
あんな大きな犬となると
大変ですよ｡
捨てる？ ﾊﾞｶ言うな｡
Abandon him? Don't be ridiculous.
途中で放り出すくらいなら➡
If I intended to abandon him, I wouldn't have taken him in from the start.
最初から
しょいこんじゃいねえさ｡
(神楽)ごめんね 定春｡
I'm sorry, Sadaharu. This umbrella's a bit small, but bear with it.
傘 ちょっと小さいけど
ｶﾞﾏﾝするね｡
ﾜﾝ！
(神楽)定春は
何にも心配しなくていいね｡
You don't have to worry about anything, Sadaharu.
(神楽)みんなが 何を言おうと
絶対 捨てたりしないね｡
No matter what anyone says, I absolutely won't abandon you.
(神楽)定春が
どんなに でっかくなっても➡
No matter how huge you become, Sadaharu, I will protect you. Understand?
私が 定春 守ってあげるからね｡
(神楽)わかった？
ﾜﾝ！
ｷｬｲﾝ！
定春！
Sadaharu!
ﾊﾞｹﾓﾉは この町から出ていけ！
Get out of town, you monster!
(神楽)ﾃﾒｴら 何しやがるんだ！
What'd you do that for?! I'll report you to the SPCA!
動物愛護団体に訴えるぞ～！
なにが動物だ！
妖怪じゃ あれは妖怪じゃ!!
What "animal"?!
It's a monster! And you're its handler!
やめてよ！
定春 普通よりでかいけど➡
Stop it! Sadaharu's bigger than normal...but he's also that much more gentle!
でも そのぶん
優しさも でかいね！
≪うるせえ！ 妖魔の使いが!!
Shut up! Monster lover!
うわっ！
ｸｯ…｡
♪♪～
おっ… おい！ なんだ？ あれ｡
H-Hey, what's happening?!
(定春の うなり声)
Monster!
≪ﾊﾞｹﾓﾝだ～！
(定春の雄たけび)
♪♪～
(人々の悲鳴)
Sadaharu!
定春 止まるｱﾙ！
Stop! No! Down! Shake! Beg! Sit!! Stay!!
ﾒｯ！ 伏せ!! お手！
おちんちん!! おちんこ!!
(神楽)あぁ ﾀﾞﾒｱﾙ…
全然 言うこと聞いてくれないよ｡
It's no use. He doesn't even hear me!
《神楽:いったい
どうして こんな…｡
How did this happen... Gin-chan... What should I do?
銀ちゃん… どうしよう！
Gin-chan!
銀ちゃ～ん！》
(ﾏｽｺﾐ)今回のことは いったい
どう責任とられるつもりですか？
How do you intend to take responsibility for this?
(ﾏｽｺﾐ)どうなんですか！
どいてください!!
Tell us.
Move it! We don't have time for this!
ﾎﾞｸたち こんなことしてる場合じゃ
ないんですよ！
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)皆さん お静かに…｡
Everyone.
Please be quiet. I will explain everything at the studio.
私が ｽﾀｼﾞｵで
洗いざらい話します！
ﾃﾒｴ～ なに 仲間 売ってんだ～!!
Damn you! Why're you selling out your friends?
見てください！
こういう連中なんです!!
Look at them! This is what kind of people they are!
撮れてる？ 撮れてる？
Are you rolling tape? Did you get that?
ｸｿｯ… これじゃ
埒があきませんよ 銀さん｡
Shit! We're not getting anywhere like this, Gin-san! If this continues, Sadaharu will be...
このままじゃ 定春が…｡
♪♪(阿音)｢ね～んね～ん ころりよ
おころりよ～｣
Rock-a-bye-baby...
Go to sleep...
♪♪｢ﾏｽｺﾐ よい子だ ねんねしな～｣
You've been good reporters...fall asleep...
All of a sudden, I feel sleepy...
あれ？ なんだか急に眠気が…｡
おいおい なんだ？ こりゃ｡
Hey, hey, what's going on?
(狛子の吠え声)
うおっ なんだ？ ｺｲﾂ｡
定春… 小さい定春だ！
Whoa! What's this? Sadaharu? It's a mini Sadaharu!
(阿音)まぁ珍しい… 狛子が
私たち以外の人になつくなんて｡
How unusual. Komako never acts friendly towards anyone but us.
How do you do?
(阿音)お初に お目見えするわね｡
私たち美人巫女姉妹➡
We are the lovely miko sisters, Ane and Mone.
阿音 ｱﾝﾄﾞ 百音｡
(笛の音)
(阿音)ｱﾅﾀたちに
あの巨大な犬を➡
We are the ones who entrusted that huge dog with you.
預かっていただいていた者で
ございます｡
♪♪～
(沖田)そこのﾊﾞｹﾓﾉ 止まりなさい！
You there, monster, stop!
お前 いったい
何ｷﾛで散歩してんだ！
Do you know how fast you're walking that dog? Stop right now!
今すぐ 停車しなさい！
Does it look like I'm walking my dog?
(神楽)これが
散歩に見えるのか？ ﾎﾞｹ!!
I'd have stopped a long time ago, if I could.
(神楽)止まれたら
とっくに止まってるんだよ！
(神楽)ﾊﾞｶだろ！ お前 ﾊﾞｶだろ!!
You really are an idiot, aren't you? Big idiot!
(沖田)はい 公務執行妨害で逮捕！
おまわりさんの心を傷つけた!!
Okay, we'll arrest you for obstruction of justice. You hurt a police officer's feelings.
You're an idiot! A real idiot!
(神楽)ﾊﾞｶだ！ お前は ﾊﾞｶだ!!
しゃあねえな…
力ずくでも止めるぜ！
Then you leave me no choice. I'll stop you by force.
やめろ～！
Don't do it!
あばよ！
(衝撃音)
Bye bye.
ｸﾞﾊﾊ… お前が ｢あばよ｣！
You're the one that goes bye-bye!
あぁ 危なかった…｡
That was close.
What?!
(神楽)なにぃ!? ｺﾗ 離すｱﾙ!!
このｻﾃﾞｨｽﾄ！
Hey! Let go, you sadist!
(沖田)ｻﾃﾞｨｽﾄは ﾃﾒｴでい！
You're the sadist.
Hey, Sogo.
(土方)お～い 総悟!!
危ねえぞ～！
Look out!
土方さん？
Hijikata-san?
(土方)ﾌｯ…｡
撃てい！
(発射音)
Fire!
(沖田)土方 この野郎!!
(爆発音)
Hijikata, you bastard!
うわぁ なんか➡
Things are really getting out of hand, Gin-san.
えらいことになってますよ
銀さん｡
心配するな 新八！
Don't worry, Shinpachi.
ｵﾚたちは 捨て犬を育てた
善良な市民だ！ 罪はない!!
We're just good citizens, who took care of an abandoned dog. We've done nothing wrong.
(阿音)狛神は 龍穴という大地の
気の流れが噴出する穴｡
The Dog Deity is a servant of the gods...
なかでも 最も大きな穴 黄龍門を
守るべき 神の子なのです！
A guardian deity of the Koryumon,
[Note: Koryumon = Golden Dragon Gate Ryuketsu = Dragon Hole]
the very largest of the Ryuketsu, holes from which all the chi on Earth spews forth...
おいおい！ いきなり出てきて➡
Hey, why'd you show up out of nowhere and start talking all this nonsense?
なに わけのわからねえこと
言ってんだ！
肛門の話なら よそで やってくれ｡
You can talk about komon somewhere else.
[Note: a word play on the similarity between Koryumon = golden dragon gate and komon = anus/butt hole]
(阿音)誰も そんな話してねえよ！
No one's talking about such a thing!
We are the shrine miko who have guarded the Koryumon for generations.
(阿音)私たちは代々
黄龍門を守ってきた神殿の巫女｡
しかし 天人は 我々を追い出し➡
But the Amanto drove us away and built the Terminal over the Koryumon.
黄龍門の上に
ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙを建ててしまった｡
So, we lost our jobs, and in order to earn a living, were forced to give up being shrine maidens.
(阿音)おかげで
私たちは 職を失って➡
生活苦のために
神子まで手放すことに…｡
生活苦で
神の子 捨てちゃったの？
You dumped your sacred charge because you were broke?
しようがないでしょ！
お金がないんだから!!
We had no choice! We were dirt poor!
でも なんで 突然
あんなになっちゃったんですか？
But why did he turn into that all of a sudden?
(百音)
狛神は おとなしい生き物です｡
The Inugami is a docile creature, but once it's strength is unleashed, it transforms into the horrific Jyushin.
[Note: Inugami means Dog God. And Jyushin is a Beast God.]
一度 力を解き放つと
恐るべき獣神へと➡
姿を変えてしまいます｡
ただ儀式も行わず 覚醒なんて…｡
But it's hard to believe it was awakened without doing the ceremony.
儀式って？
Ceremony?
A crimson fruit and the blood of a mountain goat shall release the power of Kamiko.
[Note: Kamiko means "God Child" and is probably Sadaharu's real name.]
紅き果実と山羊の血を与えん｡
さすれば 神子の力 解き放たれり｡
紅き果実と山羊の血？
A crimson fruit and blood of a mountain goat?
山羊の血っていうか乳よ!!
要は牛乳よ！
"Blood of a mountain goat" refers to the liquid that comes out of breasts. In other words, milk.
(百音)果実は
いちごとか やってましたわね｡
"Fruit" means... You were feeding him strawberries, weren't you? Cheap, nearly rotten, ones.
(百音)腐りかけの安いﾔﾂ｡
いちごと…｡
牛乳…｡
Strawberries, and...
Milk...
いちご！
牛乳!!
Strawberries...
Milk...
いちご牛乳～！
Strawberry milk!
I'll give you strawberry milk! So please just calm down!
(神楽)いちご牛乳あげるから
だから➡
お願いだから おとなしくしてよ！
(花野ｱﾅ)え～ 凶悪な巨大犬は
現在 あのように➡
The evil giant dog has climbed on top of O-Edo Dome.
大江戸ﾄﾞｰﾑの上に
逃げ込んでいます｡
(花野ｱﾅ)なお
本日 行われる予定だった➡
Today's scheduled Aliens versus Yakuza game will be cancelled. The fans are furious.
ｴｲﾘｱﾝｽﾞ 対 ﾔｸｻﾞｰｽﾞ戦は
中止になるようです｡
ﾌｧﾝも激怒してるもようです｡
(沖田)土方 死ね～！
Hijikata, die!
(土方)お前が死ね～!!
(花野ｱﾅ)あれ？ ﾌｧﾝじゃねえな｡
Huh? Those aren't fans.
You're the one who'll die!
ちなみに中止になった試合の
莫大な損害は➡
That aside, the giant dog's owners will be responsible for the huge losses
すべて 巨大犬の飼い主が
負担することに…｡
resulting from the cancellation of today's game.
うわっ！
This is crazy! We can't have him causing any more damage!
冗談じゃねえぞ！
これ以上 暴れられてたまるか!!
ｷｬﾊﾞｸﾗで貯めたお金が
ﾊﾟﾊﾟに買ってもらった家がﾊﾟｰになる｡
All the money I saved by working at the hostess club!
I'm going to lose the house my sugar daddy bought me!
あっ 銀ちゃん！ あっ 定春～!!
Gin-chan!
Sadaharu!
うわっ！
(悲鳴)
いい？ ｱﾀｼたちが あのこの覚醒を
解く呪文を唱え終わるまで➡
Listen to me. Until we complete the incantation to undo his transformation,
少しの間でいいから
時間を稼いで｡
you need to buy us some time.
１分… １分でいいわ｡
One minute... One minute is all we need.
(神楽)銀ちゃ～ん！
Gin-chan!
Don't hurt him... Don't hurt Sadaharu!
定春を… 定春をいじめないで！
定春 苦しんでるよ！
Sadaharu is suffering!
(神楽)助けて って言ってたよ！
Say you'll help him!
手加減なんかしちゃﾀﾞﾒよ｡
Don't be too easy on him. Attack as if you were trying to kill him,
殺す気でいきなさい！
or else, he'll kill you.
じゃないと… 死ぬわよ！
うおぉ～っ！
(定春の うなり声)
No way, no way, no freakin' way! One minute? I won't last ten seconds! Come on!
ﾑﾘﾑﾘ ﾑﾘﾑﾘ～！ こんなもん
１分どころか 10秒もつか!!
おい！ って聞いてねえし!!
No one told me about this!
なに あの人たち！
ﾎﾝﾄに勝手な姉妹!!
Who are those people?! Those sisters are totally self-absorbed!
おい それ
ちゃんと 呪文 唱えてんのか!?
Hey, are they really chanting the incantation?! Looks awfully random to me!
ものすごい適当に見えんだけど！
話しかけんな～！ もう一回
最初から やり直しだろうが!!
Don't talk to us! Now we have to start over from the beginning!
(２人)えぇ～!?
(阿音)出だし 何だっけ… 忘れた｡
Uh-oh, how did the beginning go again? I forgot. Nanmaida...? Nope.
[Nanmaida is short for Namu Amida Butsu...]
(阿音)ﾅﾝﾏｲﾀﾞ… 違うな｡
(足音)
(定春の雄たけび)
うわ～っ！
(定春の吠え声)
うわぁ～っ!!
新八！
Shinpachi!
銀さん！
Gin-san!
定春… おいたも たいがいに…｡
Sadaharu...
enough of this!
銀ちゃん やめて～！
Gin-chan! Stop!
(定春の吠え声)
Sadaha...
定…｡
ぎっ…！
銀ちゃん!!
Gi--!
Gin-chan!
うっ… うぅっ…｡
Damn... now I'm seeing things!
《ｸｿったれ…
妙なもんが見えやがる》
♪♪～
うわっ あぶなっ！
Look out!
銀さ～ん！
Gin-san!
Hey! You interrupted the incantation again...
ちょっと！ また 呪文が途中で…｡
(笛の音)
ﾃﾒｴら～ この非常時に なに
合ｺﾝみてえなこと やってんだ～！
Damn you two! We have an emergency!
(笛の音)
This is no time to play some stupid party game!
(阿音)何よ 何が言いたいの？
ｱﾝﾀら まさか
その笛 外れないの？
(笛の音)
What? What are you trying to say? Don't tell me you can't get that flute out?
だから どっちのﾋﾟｰよ？ それは
｢はい｣か ｢いいえ｣か｡
(笛の音)
Which is it? "Yes" or "No"?
だから
どっちだって言ってんだろうが！
I'm asking you which!
(笛の音)
(２人)ん？
(吠え声)
(２人)ｷﾞｬ～ 出た～！
There it is!
On no, we forgot those two!
あっ あの２人 忘れてきた！
百音！
Mone.
うお～ 逃げてる！
They can run like that?!
Gross! They look like some new freaky animal!
(阿音)気持悪っ！
なんか 別の生き物!!
でもあれ 要は二酸化炭素を
お互い 交換してるだけで➡
But they're only exchanging carbon dioxide. They're going to suffocate each other!!
苦しくなる一方ですよ！
(阿音)虫の息だ｡
They're barely breathing. They're already barely breathing.
すでに虫の息だ！
(神楽)お～い！
歯ぁ 食いしばれ おらぁ～！
Clench your teeth!
(２人)取れた！
歯も取れた！
It came out!
So did my teeth! Why'd you tell me to clench my teeth!
ﾃﾒｴが
歯を食いしばれって言うから！
Don't worry about it. They'll grow back.
(神楽)気にするなｱﾙ
また生えるよ｡
(みんな)ｷﾞｬ～！
Hey, what're you going to do now? The flute's broken!
ちょっと どうすんですか!?
笛も壊れちゃいましたよ！
(狛子の吠え声)
狛子！
Komako!
Now that it's come to this, our only chance is to awaken Komako and pit her against Sadaharu!
かくなるうえは 狛子を覚醒させて
対抗させるしかないわ！
百音～！
(笛の音)
Mone!
Onmakayashabazarasatoba!
ｵﾝﾏｶｼｬﾊﾞｻﾞﾗｻﾄﾊﾞ！
(笛の音)
Awaken! Inugami!
(阿音)目覚めよ 狛神！
(笛の音)
(吠え声)
ちっさ！ なんですか これ!!
Tiny! What's with this?! Now it's a runt with a scary face!
顔 ｺﾞﾂくなっただけで 何も
変わってないじゃないですか！
(みんな)あっ！
Komako is the Inugami of Protection! She won't be fazed by minor problems!
(阿音)狛子は 守りを司る狛神｡
ちょっとや そっとじゃ
抜けないわよ！
(吠え声)
あれは結界!?
(阿音)さっ 早く！
Is that a force field?!
Now! Quickly!
(阿音)みんなには 今から
ｷｬｯﾁﾎﾞｰﾙをしてもらいます｡
Now you all have to play catch with me.
Play catch?!
(銀時たち)ｷｬｯﾁﾎﾞｰﾙ!?
This ball is loaded with the power of genriki.
[Note: Genriki are powers attained through ascetic practices]
ここに
私が験力を込めた 球があるわ｡
これを 投げ合って
五芒星を描ければ➡
By throwing this to each other and tracing a five-pointed star,
この球場に
巨大な呪法陣を敷けるのよ｡
we can lay a huge magical formation on this field.
五芒星は
陰陽五行の 相生相克を表す➡
The five-pointed star represents the relationships between
宇宙万物の除災清浄となる
いわば 強力な魔除け｡
Yin, Yang and the five natural elements.
It's a powerful charm that cleanses calamity from all things in the Universe.
And, if we can seal him inside, it may revert the awakening of the Inugami.
それに あのこを閉じ込めれば➡
狛神の覚醒も解けるかもしれない｡
Teacher, your lecture put Kagura-san to sleep.
先生 神楽さんが 授業に
ついていけなくて 寝ています｡
ただ１つ 問題なのは➡
The one problem is that we'll have to trap him.
閉じ込めなければいけない
ってこと｡
So that means, we'll have to surround Sadaharu and
それじゃあ 定春を囲い➡
その攻めに耐えつつ 五芒星を？
create a five-pointed star while withstanding his attacks? That's impossible!
そんなの ﾑﾁｬですよ！
But if it's the only way to save Sadaharu, we'll do it.
(神楽)定春 助けるには
ﾑﾁｬでも やるしかないよ！
で ｷｬｯﾁﾎﾞｰﾙって何？
So, what is "play catch"?
やっぱり ﾑﾁｬだよ｡
We're all going to die...
(吠え声)
This is no time to bicker! Everyone, take your positions!
四の五の言ってる暇は ないわ！
みんな 位置について！
♪♪～
Okay! Play ball!!
よっしゃ～ ﾌﾟﾚｲﾎﾞ～ｲ！
Hey! Where're you throwing?!
おい～ どこ投げてんだ！
If you drop the ball, the spell will be useless!
球を落としたら 験力が ﾊﾟｰよ！
絶対 落としちゃﾀﾞﾒ!!
You absolutely must not drop it!
Now you tell me!
それを 先に言え～！
おらぁ… 捕った！
I got it!
Shinpachi! I always knew you were a kid who could do it if he tried!
新八～ ｵﾒｴは
やればできる子だと 思ってたぞ！
ｲﾀﾀﾀ…｡
(新八の絶叫)
Mone, catch!
(阿音)百音 捕れ～！
(笛の音)
なにやってんだ ﾃﾒｴ！
What're you doing, damn you!
Make it! Make it!
間に合え 間に合え 間に合え～！
Get over there! Over there!
銀ちゃん さすがね！
神楽～ いくぞ！
Gin-chan, way to go.
Heads up, Kagura!
ｷﾞｬ～！
ｹﾞｯ！
えぇ～！ 新八
なんで そんな所にいるんだ!!
Shinpachi! What're you doing over there?!
ﾀﾞﾒだ ｶﾊﾞｰ 間に合わねえ！
It's no use. I can't get to it!
(神楽の掛け声)
She kicked it!
(阿音)蹴った～！
It's heading to the fifth player!
ようやく ５人目！
Huh? Aren't you the fifth player?
あれっ ５人目って
ｱﾝﾀじゃなかったっけ？
Was I?
そうだっけ？
ｹﾞｯ！ 誰も いねえ～!!
Nobody's there!
Mone?!
(阿音)百音！ ﾑﾘよ!!
You can't! There's no way you can handle such a mean fastball! Get out of the way!
ﾄﾞﾝ臭いｱﾝﾀが そんな豪速球！
逃げて!!
姉上 もう やめましょう｡
Big sister... We can't quit now. We have to finish this.
途中で 放り出すのは｡
(百音)あのこを あんなﾊﾞｹﾓﾉに
してしまったのは➡
We're the ones who let that puppy become a monster.
私たちです｡
Whatever the reason, we neglected our responsibility.
どんな事情があったにせよ➡
１つの命を 捨てるようなことを
してしまったのだから｡
でも 彼らは
あのこが どんな姿になろうと➡
But these people never abandoned him no matter what he turned into.
決して 手放そうとしなかった｡
ただ 一人の家族として➡
They cared for and protected him as a member of their family.
あのこを必死に守ろうとしていた｡
今からでは
遅いかもしれませんが➡
It may be too late, but I want to become a member of that puppy's family.
私も あのこの家族になりたい！
だから もう逃げない！
That's why I won't run away anymore!
すべて この手で受け止めます｡
I will accept all my responsibilities in these hands.
あのこを この手で受け…｡
I will accept that puppy with these hands...
(阿音)結局 顔面かい！
And it still hits you in the face!
Ack... The ball...
あぁっ ﾎﾞｰﾙが…！
うわぁ～！
It's hopeless!
もう ﾀﾞﾒだ～！
(２人)あっ…｡
It's no use. There's no time!
(阿音)ﾀﾞﾒだ 間に合わない！
You did well.
よくやったよ お前｡
Leave the rest to me.
あとは ｵﾚに任せな｡
Sadaharu!
定春～！ 目を覚ませ～!!
Snap out of it!
うっ うわぁ…！
(定春の遠吠え)
What is that?
あれは何でしょう！
A strange light emanating from the ground...
ｸﾞﾗｳﾝﾄﾞに妙な光が… あっ あれを！
Ack! Look!
Sadaharu!
(神楽)定春～！ 定春!!
Sadaharu!!
I'm so glad... so glad you're safe!
よかった よかったｱﾙよ！ 定春…｡
Ahh...seeing her cry so happily.
あ～ぁ あんなに泣いちゃって｡
本当に家族なのですね｡
They really are a family.
Although... it's probably over now.
(阿音)でも
それも 今日で終わりよ｡
There's no way they'll let him stay after this happened.
あんなものを見て
それでも 今までどおり➡
あのこと 一緒に
暮らしていけると思ってるの？
Big Sister... Do we have any right to say anything after what happened?
姉上 私たちに 今さら
何か言う資格があると？
わかってるわよ｡
I know. I'm not such a shameless woman...
私も そこまで
ずうずうしい女じゃないっつうの｡
You guys do whatever you want. If you don't want him, we'll take him home with us.
(阿音)ｱﾝﾀらの好きにしなさいよ｡
いらないっつうなら
連れて帰るし｡
You don't have to worry. We won't abandon him ever again.
心配しなくてもいいわよ｡
もう 捨てるなんてしないし｡
I make quite a lot these days at the hostess bar.
ｷｬﾊﾞｸﾗで
結構 稼いでんのよ今は ﾌﾌﾌ…｡
はぁ ｱﾎらし｡ 今さら いちいち
そんなこと聞くんじゃねえよ｡
That's so stupid. After all we've been through, don't talk to us like that.
んなもん 決まってんだろうが｡
定春は…｡
You should know better. Sadaharu is...
Stupid show. Why did they pixellate the faces?
くだらねえ番組だな
ﾓｻﾞｲｸだらけじゃねえか｡
ん？ まだ捨ててなかったのか｡
このｶﾞﾗｸﾀ｡
You still haven't thrown away this piece of junk?
銀さ～ん 早くしないと
おいていきますよ～｡
Gin-san, hurry up or we'll leave without you.
はいよ～｡
Coming.
おい あれ持ったか？
Hey, did you bring it?
ｳﾝｺ袋｡ ﾏﾅｰを守れない飼い主に➡
The poop bags. Inconsiderate owners...
ﾍﾟｯﾄを飼う資格は ねえぞ｡
ﾜﾝｯ！
have no right to keep a pet.
Don't bark at me.
ﾜﾝｯ じゃねえよ ったく…｡
世話のかかる野郎だぜ｡
You sure caused us a lot of trouble.
(機械音)
[Thank you.]
The next episode... "Adults Only. We Wouldn't Want Anyone Immature in Here."
[After incurring huge debts in the Sadaharu fiasco, Ane gets a job working at the same hostess bar Otae works at.]
[The two wage an all-out sales war as the suckers gather at the bar.]
(若菜)え？ 栄純が東京に？
♪♪～
《栄純:悔しいけど
投げやすいな このﾏｳﾝﾄﾞ》
《軟球より手に馴染むかも》
(御幸)ｱｯﾌﾟは十分だろ 始めるぞ｡